-----====翻譯：=====-----
梅格 紫米稀飯 瀟湘夜雨
月生白水 小門柴
校對：火精靈
老兄  你他媽的想什麼呢
What the fuck are you doing, bruv?
嗨   夥計
Hiya, burberry. what's going on?
你還好吧
You cool?
不好意思我來晚了  錢帶來了嗎
Sorry I'm late and that, but... you got that money?
你不買飲料的話  下次就不要來這
You come here no more unless you buy drink.
-什麼  -我上周告訴你了
- what? - I tell you last week.
-該死的別碰我  -我會報警  滾出去
- don't fuckin' touch me. - I'll call the police. come on, get out.
你是不是把我當傻瓜?
You taking me for a idiot, yeah?
滾  你這個白癡
Fuck off out of here, you fucking dirty crackhead!
滾  再也別來這  否則我就報警
Fuck off! don't come here no more. l call the police.
我會報警
I call the police.
你來不來?
You coming or what?
-你到底來不來?  -別碰我的窗戶
- you coming or what? -  no touch my window!
-再也別回來  -媽的  整死你
- no come back! - I'll break you up and that. fuck you.
老兄  你到底來不來?
Are you coming or what, blud?
我沒時間  我很忙
Eh, I aint got all day, you know. I'm a busy man.
快點過來
So come on, man.
我都安排好了
Oi, I got this thing set, you know.
我在這呆了一晚上  就是給你安排這事
I've been out here all night trying to arrange this thing for you.
沒事  沒事
All right, boy. safe.
你一般不會在國王路見到我
You don't usually catch me up king's cross.
警察對那裡的乞丐管得挺緊的
Feds are well tight on the begging thing up there.
但這裡是我的地盤  從十歲起就在這了
But these are my blocks, though. this is where l grew up. since l was ten.
這是我的地盤  勇敢人的家
You get me? these are my ends, blud. home of the brave.
那些年我管著這裡呢
Well, it was like l was running the block in them days.
我想進商店買點喝的  行不?
Oi. I just wanna go in the shop and get a drink, yeah? cool.
老兄
Ah, blud.
知道嗎
You know what?
我把錢忘在家了
Rarr, I left my money in my yard, innit.
借我一塊錢  行不?
Show me a quid, innit.
就一塊  回家就給你
Till we get back to my house. one pound? nothing, man.
保證回家就還你
Pay you back when we get back to my yard.
就一百便士  老兄  快給我
It's a hundred pence. lt's nothing, blud. come on. yeah, yeah.
我就拿50便士  行嗎  我馬上回來
Oh, you know what, one-fifty, actually. ls that cool, yeah? safe. back in a minute.
白癡  你看什麼呢
What? what you looking at, you prick?
真是個笨蛋
What a twat.
-看  -混蛋
-look at that. -wanker!
-謝謝你  肯恩
-thank you, khan. -
太爽了  我們走
That's big. come on, let's go.
你在國王路幹什麼
King's cross. what was you doing up there?
-我在附近工作  -你肯定有份體面的工作吧?
- It's near where l work. - you must have a well nice job, innit?
看  那是我以前的家
It's my block up there still, you know. look.
掛粉簾子的那個
The one with the, erm, pink curtains.
我過去用的是藍簾子  不是粉色的
I had blue curtains, though. not pink ones, you get me?
-凱拉  你沒事吧  -沒事
- you all right, chela? - yeah, d, safe.
-好  不錯  -你去哪
- cool, cool. all right, doll. yeah? -  where are you going?
和這個傢伙談點生意
Eh, just gotta go and sort out this geezer, yeah?
-我一會來看你  好嗎  -好
- I'll come and check you later, all right? - yeah.
那是麥凱拉
That's michela, man.
她媽媽是妓女  就住在那邊
Her mum's on the game. live in that block up there.
每次她媽媽有客人  就把她趕出來消磨時間
Every time her mum's got a punter, yeah, she sends her out there to sit about.
你知道最慘的是什麼?  老兄  人人都知道
Know what the worst thing is? everyone knows, blud.
想像一下  麥凱拉知道每個人都知道
So, imagine that. michela knows that everyone knows.
這是我家  老兄  知道嗎
Ssh. this is my yard, bruv. you get me?
也...不算我家  但是我每次吸毒  都來這
Not my...my yard, but the place l come to when l got things a gwaan. you get me?
老兄  沒有人知道這個地方
Blud...no-one else knows about this place, you know.
這就像是...
This is kinda like...
我的秘密窩
..my secret den.
-我幫你把衣服掛起來吧  -我不會呆很久
- give me your coat. - l want to be in and out.
-什麼  -我辦完事就走
- what? - l just want to get on with this.
老兄  脫下衣服  休息一下
Bruv, just take off your coat. chill out, man.
酷  酷
S'cool. cool.
告訴過你  我就知道是巴寶莉牌的
All right. l told you, l knew it. burberry. sick. sick. top.
日子真不錯  這正是我想要的
Oh, my days. look that's proper tings.
老兄  正是我想要的
Proper tings, blud. proper tings.
幹嘛不和我說你有伏特加  早知道就帶可樂來了
Why you ain't tell me you had vodka? I'd have bought coke. you get me?
可樂加伏特加  我最喜歡的飲料
Vodka and coke. that's my favourite drink.
我在索霍區俱樂部裡就喝這個
It's what I drink when I'm up in the clubs in soho.
你不介意吧?
You don't mind, do you? down, man.
太棒了  太爽了
That's wicked. that's big! big!
太高興了
Bubbling.
坐  休息一下  你怎麼了
Take a seat. just relax, man. come on, what's wrong with you?
喝點東西
Come, have a little drink and that.
休息休息
Chill out.
過來
Mm...come, man.
你寂寞還是怎麼的?
Are you lonely or something?
-什麼  -你寂寞嗎
- what? - are you lonely?
-你想說什麼  老兄  -我只想結束這一切
- what you trying to say, blud? - l just want to get on with this.
好吧  他媽的
All right. fuck it.
他媽的  把錢給我
Fuck it. show me the fucking money. go on.
不錯嘛
Nice, boy.
750塊
什麼
What?
750塊
-我是說800塊的  -昨天給你50了
- l told you 800, though. - l gave you ?50 yesterday.
-你沒給  -我給了
- you didn't. - l did.
- no, you didn't. - yes, l did.
呃  那50呀  那50塊只是餘款
Yeah, yeah, that 50, that's just a residual, blud.
-什麼  -餘款
- what? - residuals.
道上就是這麼辦事的  老兄  明白嗎?
That's how tings go on the street, bruv. get me?
-那不是餘款  -是  是餘款
- that's not a residual. - yeah, it is.
-餘款是  是一種誠信的體現  -嗯  嗯  誠信
- a residual is a... It's a form of royalty. - yeah, yeah, royalty. yeah.
誠信的契約  一種禮貌
Honourable bond. chivalry and all that.
-也就是頭期款  -對
- so that was a down payment? - yeah, yeah, yeah.
如果那是頭期款  這是剩下的錢
Right, then here's the rest.
富佬  別自作聰明
Don't get clever, you know, rich man.
那50塊只是保證我能替你解決問題  你出得起錢
That was a guarantee that l'd sort this out. and you was right for your dollars.
我查過了  你不是警察
I was checking that you weren't no feds,
你也查過我不是警察吧
You was checking that I wasn't either, innit?
-什麼  警察?  -嗯  警察
- what? feds? - feds, man.
警察  差佬  公安  條子
Po-po, 條子, five-oh, one time.
我想每個人都看得出你不是警察
Yeah, I think anybody can tell you're not a policeman.
你想說什麼
What you trying to say?
媽的  你這個自大的傢伙
You know what? easy with that stuck-up shit!
你在我地盤呢  富佬  我的地盤
This is my world you're in now, rich man. my yard!
你覺得我看上去很窮  就以為我是個傻瓜?
My god! you must think 'cause I look like some poor crackhead that's all I am.
我路子多著呢
I've got connections!
媽的  死白癡
Fuck! fucking prick!
-媽的  -麥克  怎麼了
- fuck! - michael, what's happened?
麥克?
Michael?
怎麼了
What's up?
你要去哪
Where are you going?
出去
Out.
什麼意思  我不明白  怎麼了
What do you mean? I don't understand. what's happened?
麥克  求你了
Michael, please.
-你要去哪  -出去
- where are you going? - l'm going out.
麥克  你打不打算告訴我發生了什麼了嗎
Are you going to tell me what's going on? michael?
發生了什麼  你要去哪  你要去哪
What's happened? where are you going? where are you going?
塔妮雅  看在上帝的份上
For fuck's sake, tania!
你要把這東西帶到哪  我不問別的
Where you taking his stuff? just tell me where you're going. It's all l'm asking you.
有點事  現在出去解決
Look...I have got a problem, and I am going to sort it out right now.
聽懂了嗎  現在就去
Ok? right fucking now.
麥克
Michael!
你少給了50塊  告訴過你是800塊
You came 50 pound light! l told you 800.
我只有750
Well, l've got 750!
-我們去提款機取  -不行
- we have to go to the cashpoint. - we can't.
-為什麼不行  -我沒帶卡
- why not? - I don't have my cashcard on me!
你還帶什麼了  你身上還帶什麼了
Ah...what else you got? what else you got on you? huh?
這是什麼
What the hell is this?
照片不錯   看上去你不太舒服
Ahh. nice photo. you look ill, boy.
霍...  霍..  霍拉提奧
Ho.. ho.. ho-ra-tee-o.
赫萊西奧
Horatio.
赫萊西奧·班布賴吉
Horatio bainbridge.
你說你叫湯姆
You said your name was tom.
你會四處告訴別人你叫赫萊西奧嗎?
Well, would you go around calling yourself horatio?
當然
Yeah.
-這是什麼  -我的工作證
- what the fuck is this? - It's my work pass.
我要它有什麼用  白癡
What the fuck do I want that for, you prick?
別跟我搞鬼
Listen, don't play with me, an' that.
老兄  我告訴你  我認識的人多著呢
I roll deep, blud. tellin' you.
-你不能這樣出去  -你他媽的讓...
- you can't go out like this. - get the fuck...
-讓開  -你不能走
- get out the way. - you ain't going.
-讓開  -不
- get out the way. - no.
你他媽的讓開
Get out the fucking way!
-媽的  -麥克
- fuck! - michael...
麥克  麥克  你冷靜一下
Michael, michael. you're gonna have to calm down.
我擔心你  我擔心我們
I'm worried about you. I'm worried about us.
麥克  聽著
Michael...listen.
我不管你去哪
Wherever you're going, l don't care.
我不介意   我理解  你有生意要做
I don't mind. I understand, you got business.
麥克  你要冷靜
Michael, you got to do it calm,
否則你會做壞事的
Or you're gonna do something bad.
那天晚上  這麼做管用了
Look, it worked the other night.
不  親愛的  管用了
No, it worked. It worked, darling.
求你了  再試一次  為我
Please. please try again for me. come on.
再試一次
- come on. come on. -
就是這樣  就是這樣
That's it. that's it.
再試一次  親愛的  親愛的
Come on. darling, darling, darling, darling.
阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho...
南無...
Renge kyo...
阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho...
Renge kyo.
看到了吧?  就是這樣  就是這樣
See? that's it, that's it.
阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho...
Renge kyo.
南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo.
-就是這樣  -南無阿彌陀佛
- that's it! - nam myoho renge kyo.
南無阿彌陀佛  南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo. nam myoho renge kyo.
你在外面小心點  好嗎
Now you be careful out there, all right?
南無阿彌陀佛  南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo. nam myoho renge kyo.
南無阿彌陀佛
- nam myoho renge kyo. -
南無阿彌陀佛  南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo. nam myoho renge kyo.
阿彌陀佛
..renge kyo.
南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo.
他媽的
This is fucked up, man!
那個戒指
Eh, what about that ring? uh?
-什麼  -你口袋裡的戒指
- what? - the ring in your pocket, man.
-它不只值50  -跟我有什麼關係
- that's worth a little more than 50. - ls that my problem, though? uh?
事實是你少了50塊
Fact is you came 50 pound light.
如果我沒得到我想要的  你也不會得到你想要的
If l don't get what's coming to me you ain't gonna get what's coming to you.
-金子做的是不是?  -是
- Is it gold, yeah? - yeah.
-手錶呢  -什麼
- and what about that watch? - what?
-手錶  -你沒開玩笑吧?
- the watch! - are you being serious?
-該是我的就是我的  -媽的
- I gotta get what's coming to me! - oh, fuck this.
你要去哪?  老兄
Oi, where the fuck you going? oi, blud!
老兄
Oi, blud!
老大
Eh...boss.
別這樣  別這樣
Eh, now, come on.
冷靜點  好嗎
Chill out, yeah?
我剛剛只是試試你  好嗎
I was just...just testing you, yeah?
看  你把戒指給我了
Look. you gave me the ring.
750塊我就做了  行不
I'll do it for 750, all right?
-兄弟  你去哪兒  -關你什麼事
-hoods. where you going, eh? -what's it to you?
我要給迪弄個t
I need to get a t for the b.
鸚鵡還在窗戶那裡嗎
Is the parrot in the window? huh?
那只該死的鸚鵡還在他媽的窗戶那嗎
Is the fucking parrot in the fucking window?
-沒有  -是嗎
-no. -huh?
-不  沒在  -沒在  你這個他媽的雜種
- lt's not. no. - lt's not, you fucking pinhead prick.
但是  兄弟  我正爽呢  今天是發失業金的日子
But, hoods, man, I'm rattling. lt's giro day.
-我有錢  老兄  -去你媽的
-I've got the money, hoody. -fuck off.
我們現在在做生意  夥計
Business world we're going to deal with now, blud.
來  碰一下  喝一口
Come, clink and drink.
來吧  兄弟
Come on, man.
你準備交錢了嗎?
You gonna hand over the cash, then?
我想看看我買的東西
I wanna see what l'm buying.
先交錢  兄弟
Money up front, man.
-看到我要買的東西才給錢  -先交錢
-only when l see what l'm buying. -money up front.
不行
No.
好吧
All right.
好  行啦  你想這樣玩嗎
All right, yeah? you wanna play it like that, yeah?
你會把事情搞砸的
You just fucked up.
知道嗎  會搞砸
Uh-huh. you just fucked up.
看這個
Watch this...
搞砸了
Just fucked up.
該死的你
You're fucked.
-誰  -霍德維克
-who is it? -hoodwink.
-克裡斯托  -霍德維克  怎麼樣啊
- crystal. - hoodwink. what gwaan?
-很長時間沒見到你了  -你看見迪了嗎
-long time me no see you. -have you seen d?
他昨晚來過
Him come round last night.
發生什麼事了  小迪給自己找麻煩啦
Wha'ppen? little d get himself in a trouble?
算了
It don't matter.
-我不感興趣  迪身上有錢嗎  -霍德維克...
-out of interest, did d have money on him? -hoodwink...
相信我  要是迪沒錢他是走不出那道門的
D would've never get through that front door if him was broke. trust me.
-他有多少錢  -50鎊
-how much did he have? -50 pound.
50...  他媽的50鎊
現在真的很無聊
Really boring now.
想和我談?
Talking to me?
怎麼啦  笨蛋
What up, fool?
真他媽的
For fuck's sake...
英國他媽最壞的牙買加人
Baddest bumbaclot jamaican in the united kingdom.
你死定了
Squash you.
對啊  那能行
Yeah, that'll do.
800鎊買這個很便宜  你知道嗎
This is a good buy for 800 pound, you know.
750  真是物美價廉
For 750, this is a bargain.
麥凱拉  今天你看見迪了嗎
Michela. you seen d today?
麥凱拉
Michela.
你今天看見迪了嗎
Have you seen d today?
你看到沒
Have you?
是的  他和一個人在一起
Yeah. he was with someone.
他跟誰在一起
Who was he with?
-以前沒見過他  -他長什麼樣
-ain't seen him before. -what was he like?
白人  迪說他要幫他解決問題
Some white guy. d said he was gonna sort him out.
媽的
Fuck!
操你  迪
Fuck you, d!
沒事  沒事  麥凱拉
It's ok. It's ok, michela.
沒關係  沒事的  沒事的
It's all right. It's ok. lt's ok.
這個白人張得什麼樣子?
So what was he like, this white guy?
他們去哪兒啦
Where did they go?
你知道  就像  你媽媽有時候給我錢
You know, like...your mum sometimes gives me money.
你知道  因為她需要我
You know, 'cause she needs me.
那麼  我需要你為我做點事
Well, er, l need you to do something for me.
你得告訴我迪在哪兒
You have got to tell me where d is.
我得看看
I need to look at it.
它就在這兒啊
There it is.
是啊  但可能是仿製品
Yeah, that could be a replica.
這是一隻38口徑的搶
This is a .38 snubnose.
特別是週六晚上
Saturday night special.
老兄  你知道嗎  用這個可是能造成很大破壞的
Can do some serious damage with this thing, you know, bredren.
-他們上那兒去了  -另外一個傢伙也去了?
-they went down there. -the other fella too?
是的
Yeah.
相信我  粗魯的男孩
Trust me, rude boy.
你把簡單的事情搞複雜了
You're making something simple very complicated.
-我可是個神槍手  兄弟  -給我看看槍就行了
-I'm a marksman, bruv. -just show me the gun.
-看了我滿意的話  我會付錢的  -我是個刺客
-lf l like what l see, l'll pay you. -l'm an assassin.
-我保證  -什麼  什麼
-l guarantee it. -whap, whap, whap...
好嗎  付了錢就走
All right? as soon as l've paid, l will leave.
好嗎
Yeah?
只要我一走  你就能
As soon as l've left, you can...
你就可以到這兒的煙館去  抽上一整盒
You can run down the local drug den, you can blow the whole lot.
怎麼樣?
Huh?
-把錢放在桌上  老兄  -哦  別這樣
-money on the table, bruv. -oh, come on.
別這樣  我看起來像會了槍打你嗎
Come on, do l look like l'm about to take the gun and shoot you?
不  不  你不會
No. no, you don't.
但那不是你要問你自己的問題
But that's not the question you should be asking yourself.
事實上
Fact is...
我看起來像要射你的人嗎  像嗎
Do l look like l'm about to shoot you? hm?
像嗎
Uh?
你幹嘛要以貌取人呢  有錢人
Why don't you judge me on the way l look, rich man?
我可是個嗜血的煙鬼
I'm a bloodclot crackhead.
也就是說我是個危險人物
Which means l'm a dangerous man to know.
你笑什麼
What you laughing at?
你他媽究竟在笑什麼
What the fuck are you laughing at, man?
我向上帝發誓  不要試探我  知道嗎  有錢人
I swear to god, don't test me, you know, rich man.
知道嗎  老兄  我已經殺了很多人了
Oi, I've killed nuff people, you know, blud.
滾回你的地盤  要知道你和個攜搶的煙鬼
Now, you just move back to where you come from, with the knowledge that
起了點小摩擦  竟然還能活著離開
You just had a little brush with a gun-toting crackhead and you lived.
聽懂啦
Yeah?
把錢放在桌上  給我滾出去
Put your money on the table and get the fuck out.
-把槍給我  -你他媽...
-give me the gun. -what the fuck...
-不  -給我
-no. -come on.
-滾開  你他媽在幹嘛  -你他媽把槍給我
-get off me! what the fuck are you doing? -fucking give it to me..
你真是瘋了
You're crazy...
你他媽這個骯髒的雜種  把槍給我
You fucking dirty fucker. give it to me!
給我!
Give it to me!
給我  給我  你
Come on! come on! come on, you...!
-你這個雜種  -你在做什麼
-you fucker! -what you doin'?
迪
D?
滾開
Get off!!
你他媽的同性戀
You fucking gaybo!
上帝啊  迪  把那小東西收好
For fuck's sake, d, put that wee thing away.
霍斯!
Hoods!
發生什麼事了  老兄
What's going on, man?
還好嗎
Fine?
那他媽的是誰?
Who the fuck is that?
你從什麼時候起開始當鴨了
Since when have you been selling your arse? huh?
Since when have you been selling your arse?
-霍斯  兄弟  我沒有  -是嗎
-hoods, man, l ain't selling my arse, blud. -oh.
那我進來的時候你們在幹什麼
So what were you doing, huh, when l came in?
-你賺了多少錢?  -我說過了...
-how much money you been making? -l said...
我知道你掙錢了  昨晚你到克裡斯托那兒去了
I know you been making money 'cause you was over at crystal's last night!
-你為什麼不告訴我?  -我沒有在當鴨
-why didn't you tell me? -l ain't selling my arse.
不告訴我是因為你欠我錢  你他媽的煙鬼
You didn't tell me because you owe me money, you little fucking crackhead.
你他媽的欠我錢
You owe me fucking money!
給我他媽的下樓去
Get up the fucking stairs!
不  等等
No, wait, wait.
我有幾句話要跟迪說
I've got to have words with d.
要是在走之前再看到你
If l see you before I've gone,
我會他媽毀了你的
I'll fucking ruin you.
同性戀
Gaybo.
霍斯  兄弟  輕點  輕點
Eh, hoods, man. low it, low it!
你他媽在幹什麼  兩星期前怎麼跟你說的
What the fuck are you doing? what did l say two weeks ago?
-不是讓你躲起來嗎  -我躲了  那兒都沒去
-didn't l tell you to lie low? -l've been lying low! l ain't been nowhere!
那你那個小白臉是哪裡來的?
So where did your man gay bollocks come from?
-我在街上遇到他的  -他該死的到底從哪兒來的
-l met him on the street. -where did he fucking come from?
-我是在街上遇到他的  -哦  是嗎
-l met him on the street! -oh, did you?
在他媽的街上碰到的?
On the fucking street?
輕點  嘿  霍斯  求你  別打了
Hey, low it! hey, hoods, please...! stop!
-你他媽笨蛋...  -我發誓  我什麼都沒告訴他
-you fucking stupid... -l swear. l ain't told him nothing, man!
媽的  你要幹什麼  霍斯  不要  媽的
Shit. what are you doing, hoods? don't! shit...!
-這看起來像什麼  -媽的  媽的
-what does it look like? -shit! shit!
在我們幹那事後三個禮拜以後
You don't go picking up some gaybo pervert off the street
你竟然隨便把個變態同性戀給帶回來了
Three weeks after what we've done.
你他媽不要
You fucking don't...
-冷靜點  -我這麼做只是為了活命
-peace! -l'm going down for life.
霍斯  可我什麼都沒做啊  兄弟
Hoods, l didn't even do anything, though, man!
-夥計  -不  你他媽做了
-blud! -yes, you fucking did!
媽的
Shit!
媽的  它在這兒  媽的
Fuck, it's in here! fuck!
上帝啊  一直在我腦子裡
Jesus christ, it's in here!
迪 那個男人可能是特別行動組的
Your man down there could be special branch, d!
哦  媽的
Oh, fuck!
好了  兄弟  呼吸
Ok, man, just breathe.
南無阿彌陀佛  南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo. nam myoho renge kyo.
南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo!
好了  問你個問題
Ok, so...so l got a question that l got to ask you.
是不是關於你的錢?  我欠你的錢?
About your money? the money that l owe you?
霍斯  我一直在想辦法弄錢  但佷不順利
Hoods, listen. I'm trying to get your money but things are just way out...
我一直在想辦法弄錢  我發誓
I've been trying to get your money, l swear!
一切都搞砸了  記得嗎  我去了你家
Everything's messed up. remember? l came to your house
-你在那兒很安全  記得嗎  -確實
-and you were safe about it. remember? -exactly.
昨晚你在我東西邊上打轉了  是不是
You came round my gaff last night.
是嗎
Hm?
那麼我的槍他媽在哪裡
so where's my fucking gun?
我的槍他媽在哪裡
So where's my fucking gun?
我不知道你的槍在哪兒
I don't know where your gun is.
-我沒有拿你的槍  我發誓  -上帝  好吧
-l ain't taken your gun, l swear. -jesus! ok. all right.
原來我的0.38好端端的在我的浴缸底下
So how come my .38 was nice and snug under my bath, right?
昨晚你來了  然後今天早上  它就沒了
And you come over last night, and then by this morning it's gone?
我發誓  霍斯  我發誓  我沒有去過浴室
I swear, hoods. l swear, man. l didn't go in your bathroom, blud.
我更本沒進過浴室  霍斯  我一直都在前廳
I didn't even go in your bathroom, hoods. l was in your front room the whole time.
記得麼  我一直都在前廳
I was in the front room the whole time. remember?
求你了  我發誓  我真沒拿...
- please. l swear, l didn't take... -
媽的  去你的
- oi, fuck you! -
等等  老大  我發誓 那一定是賽夫的手下
Shit, hold on. lt must have been one of sef's crew, man. l swear.
他們來過的
They came round.
老大  還記得麼  他們來過的
Do you remember? yeah? they came round, man.
賽夫是來買白粉的
Sef came to buy weed, yeah.
他和2個你從未見過面的人一起
He was with those two guys you never met before.
雷和格雷
Ray and gary.
格雷很擅長使用武器  霍斯  我發誓...
That gary's well into his weapons. hoods, l swear...
-媽的  混球  -我發誓!
-fucking bollocks!! -l swear!
那幾個從來沒來過的混帳怎麼可能
How could some fucker who has never been round my gaff before
知道槍在哪裡?
Know where to look?
老大  因為是雷  聽我說
That's why it's ray, man! l'm telling you. he lives...
他住的那個公寓
He lives in them flats.
他們住的那個公寓  劍橋塔公寓
He lives in them flats, man. cambridge tower.
和你住的公寓一模一樣  我媽的發誓
It's just the same as your block up there, hoods, l swear. lt's the same. fuck!
你也知道  那把槍能帶來好運
That gun has got a hit on it, as well you know.
它跟了我他媽的至少15年
That gun has got a minimum of 15 fucking years of my life on it.
-在哪裡?  -天哪
- where is it? - for fuck's sake...
迪  他媽的槍在哪兒?
Where the fuck is it, d?
操!
Fuck you!
夠了!
That's enough!
他欠你多少?
How much does he owe you?
多少錢?
How much?
如果我幫他還  能放了他嗎?
If I pay you his debt, will you leave?
多少錢?
How much?
270英鎊
我沒告訴你叫你呆在那兒嗎?
Did I not tell you to stay in that fucking room?
你以為他媽的是誰?
Who the fuck are you? hm?
警察?  過來抓我的嗎?
The old bill? you come to nick me, have you?
是嗎?  來呀  快來  來抓我呀  死條子
Yeah? well, go on, then. go on. fucking cuff me up, officer!
快來啊  來銬我呀  死條子
Come on, then. fucking cuff me up, officer!
嘿?  來銬我呀!  哦  不  不  我明白了
Hey? eh? cuff me fucking up! no? no, l thought not.
你這死同性戀是過來花錢享樂的
You baggy gaybo pervert coming round here to spend your money
來操男人  真不要臉
On a young man's arse. shame on you!
覺得自己有錢?  啊?
Think you're rich do you? huh?
從口袋拿出錢扔我是嗎?  啊?
Flashing your cash at me, in your suit, huh?
那好  看看吧
Well, check it out.
媽的好好看看吧
Check it fucking out!
霍斯...  霍斯...  霍斯
Hoods...hoods...hoods.
看到了嗎?
You see?
我說過了  他不是警察  不是嗎?
Look, l told, l told, l told you he weren't feds, innit?
我還讓你得到這些錢呢  老大
And l got your money for you as well, man.
我只是想...
I was...l-l-l was gonna..
為了老大你  我出賣自己的肉體
I was gonna sell my arse for you, hoody. fuck!
出賣自己的肉體  幫你賺到這些錢
Yeah! l was gonna sell my arse to get you the money.
我沒拿過你的槍
I never took your gun, man.
老大  我說了  是雷干的  是雷!
It was ray. l'm telling you, it was ray, man.
他住在...  住在...  劍橋塔公寓
He...he lives in them... them places. ln..in cambridge towers.
和你住的地方一模一樣
They're the same as your place.
所以他知道浴室的事
That's how he knew about the bath thing.
喂?
- - yeah?
賽夫  是我  霍斯
Sef. lt's the hood.
等等  等下  好嗎
Hold on, mate. hold on a sec, yeah?
霍斯  請等一下  好嗎
Hoods, mate, just give me a second, yeah?
-你在幹嗎呢?  -你看到我的耐克上衣了嗎
- what are you doing? - seen my nike top?
我在打電話  給我滾出去
I'm on the phone. get out!
出去
Get out, man!
媽
Mum!
霍斯  怎麼了
Hoods. 's up?
你在哪裡?
Where are you?
在我媽家裡  怎麼了  老兄
Just chillin' at my mum's yard, dude. what's up?
沒什麼  我要過來
Don't matter. l'm coming over.
在劍橋公寓外見
Meet me outside cambridge tower.
叫雷和那個昨晚一起來我公寓的
And bring ray and that other little fucker
叫格雷的小傢伙一起過來
Who came round my gaff last night. gary.
霍斯  老兄  不行  我學校有事呢
Hoods, mate, l can't. l've got college.
我管你什麼學校  給你10分鐘
Fuck your college. ten minutes.
你最好慢慢祝福祈禱...
You better hope and pray...
是雷拿了我的槍
...that ray has got my gun.
南無阿彌陀佛  南無阿彌陀佛
Nam myoho renge kyo. nam myoho renge kyo.
雷  我是賽夫  你和格雷一起嗎?
Ray. lt's sef. you with gary, yeah?
霍斯想要見我們
Hoodwink wants to meet us.
不是好像  是要馬上
No. like, now.
我他媽的什麼都不清楚
I don't fucking know.
馬上去車庫  切記叫上格雷
Just get to the garages, yeah? make sure gary comes with you.
你他媽的怎麼了?
What the fuck is up with you, man?
老兄  你不用這麼害怕霍斯的
You don't take on the hood like that, blud.
相信我  錢  再找幾個傢伙搶過來就行了
Trust me to pick some fucking nutter to rob.
那你也相信我  搶過來後  買把槍放身邊
Trust me to pick some nutter to buy a gun off.
-你說什麼?  -我說
- what you say? - l said,
找幾個瘋子  蠢蛋  搶完錢  買把槍防身
Trust me to pick some fucked-up, crackhead nutcase to buy a gun off.
媽的跟我有什麼關係
Want a fucking go with me, yeah?
告訴你  我會打爆你的頭
I will bust a cap in your skull, l'm telling you.
該死的膽小鬼
Fucking prick.
知道他是誰嗎?  霍斯  老兄  是  霍德維克
Do you know who that was? lt's hoodwink, blud. lt's the hood.
他媽的我才不怕他
I couldn't give a shit.
瘋子我可見過不少
I've met some nutters in my time, but...
但像你剛剛那樣的瘋子還真沒見過
You're fucking up there, mate. right up there. shit.
我要這把槍
I want the gun.
滾蛋吧  我不會把該死的槍給你的
Fuck off, man. you ain't getting the fucking gun.
你知道嗎
You know what?
你還是走吧
In fact, ride's up, man.
-你該走了  -我要槍
- time to go. - l want the gun.
-我不會給你的  -我給你錢
- you ain't getting it. - I paid for it.
-不行  -我幫你還了債了
- you ain't. - I paid your debt.
你自找的  我可沒叫你那麼做  讓開
That's your problem. l didn't ask you to do that. step, man.
你在幹什麼  你滾吧  你要我一槍殺了你嗎
What are you doing? get out of the way. do you want me to shoot you, yeah?
我他媽的早就跟你說了  這可不是鬧著玩兒的
I fucking told you already. this thing can do some serious damage.
你還想讓我再揍你幾拳嗎
Do you want me to tear off your face?
求你了  我可是說真的  趕緊滾吧
Come on. l'm being serious. just fuck it off.
從哪來回哪去吧  你到底怎麼了  趕緊滾吧
Go back to your rich man life. what's wrong with you. come on, get out of the way.
那要不這樣  你呆在這兒等霍德維克過來
You know what? I got a better idea. you stay here, yeah? wait for hoodwink.
-我跟你拜拜了  有錢人  -把該死的槍給我啊
- l'll be seeing you later, rich man. - give me the fucking gun!
把槍給我
Give me the gun!
把那該死的槍給我啊
Give me the fucking gun!! give me the gun!
我操
Oh, shit!
你他媽的饒了我吧
Oi, for fuck's sake, man, just...
我操  我操  我操  我操  我操
Fuck. fuck. fuck. fuck. fuck. fuck.
別踢了
Stop this shit!
我操  我操  你這個混蛋  我操
You fuck. fuck. you fucker. fuck.
操死你
Fucking hell!
有錢人  你在幹什麼
Oi, rich man. what are you doin'?
你這該死的  我操死你
You fucker. you fucker. you...
操死你
Fucker!
他媽的
Oh...shit!
啊
Arghh!
有錢人
Oi, rich man!
我不知道哪招惹你了
Look, l don't know what your beef is, man...
求你了  兄弟
Oi, please, blud.
我只是個小煙鬼
I'm just a little crackhead, man.
有錢人
Rich man...
你這蠢蛋
you fucker!
你這該死的...
You fuuuuck!
我哪知道他怎麼突然要見我們
I don't know why he wants to see us!
-你生什麼氣呀  -別問我了  我他媽的不知道
- what you getting vexed for, man? - stop asking me. l don't fucking know!
-他聽上去是不是很生氣?  -他媽的誰知道
- did he sound pissed off? - fuck's sake.
我操
Shit.
霍斯  怎麼啦
Hoods, what's wrong man?
-你從我浴室裡拿走了什麼  -什麼都沒拿
- what did you take from my bathroom? - I took nothing, man.
-你拿了什麼  -什麼都沒拿  霍斯
- what did you take from my bathroom? - I took nothing, hoods!
-我他媽的槍在哪  -我什麼都不知道啊
- where's my fucking gun? - I don't know nothing about no gun.
-啊  -我的槍在哪
- ahh! - where's my gun?
-他媽的槍在哪  小混蛋  -我不知道什麼槍啊
- where's my...fucking...gun, you prick! - I don't know nothing about no gun.
-那怎麼迪說你知道  -什麼?
- why does d say you do? - wha..?
-為什麼迪說你偷了我的槍  -我不知道你在說什麼
- why does d say you stole my gun? - I don't know what you're talking about.
誰都不許動
None of you three move.
喂  保羅  你好嗎
Hello, paul. how're you doing?
恩
Aye.
是今天嗎  我以為是...
Oh, it was today was it? I thought it was, er...
我以為是明天
I thought it was tomorrow.
不  沒問題的
No, no, no, no, no. no problem, man.
沒問題  為了你會讓鸚鵡一直在窗台上
No, the...the parrot is always in the window for you, man.
我大概10分鐘就可以到了
Huh? I can be round in, er...about ten minutes.
你只要敲門就行了
Ok, just, er...knock on the... knock on the door.
塔妮雅在那兒  她會招待你喝咖啡的
Tania's there and she'll... get her to make you a cup of tea.
10分鐘好嗎  那再見  保羅
Ten minutes. ok? see you then, paul.
-我們不知道槍的事  -他媽的閉嘴
- we don't know nothing about no gun. - shut the fuck up!
我的槍不見了  我得找回來
My gun was taken, and I want it back.
不管誰出面  總之得拿回來
I don't care who brings it back.
什麼型號的槍
What type of gun was it?
是什麼...  什麼型號的槍
Wh...what type of gun...is it?
是一個.38
It's a...it's a .38.
哪種  像個塌鼻子嗎
What, like a snubnose?
對
Yeah.
-好的  -是的  就得這樣
- nice. - yeah, yeah, I like that.
我要拿回我的槍
I want my gun back.
我才不管是誰去幫我拿回來的
I don't care who brings it back.
我們真沒拿  肯定是迪干的
We ain't got it, though. It must be d.
-那就去找迪  -要是找不到他呢
- go and see d. - what if we can't find him?
這煙鬼到處亂竄  連個住所都沒有
That crackhead's all over the place. I swear he ain't even got a place to live.
你知道那個大倉庫嗎
You know those warehouses up on...
-在糖果屋大道上的那個  -知道了
- sugarhouse lane. hmm? - yeah.
10分鐘前  他在那兒做鴨子呢
Ten minutes ago, he was selling his arse up there.
-做鴨子  -是的
- selling his arse? - yeah.
什麼意思  迪真是個瘋子嗎
What do you mean? D's some sort of battie-boy?
雷  他太噁心了
Rarr, that is nasty.
所以我是你們的話  我會盡快過去
Yeah, so if I was you, I'd get up there, quick as, ok?
就用我的表計時
I'm watching this watch and...
給你們一小時
You've got an hour. tops.
我發誓  兄弟
Ey, I swear, blud.
我發誓  要是你再這樣衝過來的話
I swear, you know. If you move to me like that again...
我會他媽的開槍的
I'm going to fucking shoot.
我會他媽的殺了你的  夥計
I will fucking shoot you, blud.
聽到了嗎  有錢人
You hear me, rich man?
有錢人  跟你說話呢
Rich man? I'm telling you, blud.
我隨時都可以開槍
Hey, I got my finger on the trigger.
兄弟  會射到你的
You gonna get shot, blud.
-我覺得事情有點不對頭  -那還能怎麼辦
-  I ain't feeling this right. - I can't let this go.
-是的  但是...  -不  你看看我
- yeah, but... - no, look at me!
我可沒拿那把槍  你也沒有
I ain't taken the gun, you ain't taken it,
格雷也沒有  所以肯定是迪干的
Gary ain't, which means d must have taken it.
我不能就這樣被他媽的白打了
I ain't getting fucked up like this without payback.
我們不用去打迪  只要拿回槍就行了
We don't need to fuck d up, we just need to get the gun.
-我們一定要給他點顏色看看  -我們只要...
- we need to fuck him up. - we just need...
他媽的  迪誣告我  他是個混蛋
Fuck that shit! d grassed me up. and he's a battie-boy.
我要去揍他  說到做到
I'm gonna fuck d up, man. straight.
格雷該死的跑到哪裡去了
Where the fuck is gary, anyway, man?
上帝啊  你給我開門
Oh, for fuck's sake, man, answer your fucking door!
我找不到我的白粉了
Oh, l can't find my weed, you know.
什麼?
What?
我有一大袋的  可是找不到了
I got a big bag of skunk l can't find.
什麼?  去你的白粉  格雷  我們要幹大事
What? fuck your weed, gary, man! we got big things to do, blud!
操  就知道吸毒
Fuck's sake! fucking weedhead prick.
你給我該死的快點
Hurry the fuck up!
你還真是磨磨蹭蹭的
You fucking took your time!
但你知道我要幹嘛  別管了  看看這些
Yeah, but you know how it is, cuz. anyway. fuck that. check this.
雙節棍不錯啊  夥計
- - them nunchakus are nang, blud.
-是我的  真粗魯  -拿來
- they're mine, rude boy. - oh, come on, man.
什麼?  你有T型棍啊
What? you can have that, man. that's the tonfa.
做工很好的  很棒
Proper ashwood, you know. cold.
我不去
I ain't coming.
-什麼?  -我可不會帶著武器跑過去  該死的
- what? - l ain't going tooled up. fuck that.
-我以為你是我兄弟呢  -我是啊
- l thought you was my bredren. - l am.
-那就拿著T型棍  -你說什麼?  你不來?
- then take the tonfa. - what you talking about, you ain't coming?
-我們要去拿槍啊  -拿著  賽夫
- we have to get this gun, man. - take the fucking tonfa, sef.
現在就拿
Now.
聽著
Listen, yeah?
夥計  保持冷靜  行嗎
Blud, just ke... stay calm, yeah?
行嗎
All right?
我不想再惹麻煩了  有錢人
I don't want any more trouble. l want no more trouble, rich man, all right?
我只想要這把槍  僅此而已
I just want the gun, that's all.
給我槍我就走
Just give me the gun and l'm gone.
-求你了  -不行啊  你不會想要槍的
- please. - no, man. you don't want the gun.
我一直在告訴你  有錢人
That's what l'm trying to say, rich man.
你的商業夥伴出賣你了  還是怎麼了?
Wh...? your business partner rip you off or something? huh?
你想殺了他嗎  不值的  兄弟
And you're gonna shoot him? that's bullshit, man.
等等
Wait.
是不是和戒指有關?
It's about this, innit?
你妻子離開你了  是嗎
Your wife left you, yeah?
所以你才到這裡來?
That's why you're here.
你想...  你想殺了他的相好?
So, er...now you wanna go... you wanna go shoot her new man?
是不是?
Is that it?
想殺了那個雜種
Gonna go murk that prick.
不值得的  夥計
Ain't worth it, blud.
-你根本不知道在說什麼  -我知道
- you don't know what you're talking about. - yeah. l do.
我知道我在說什麼  夥計  好不好?
I do know what l'm talking about, blud. all right?
沒有女人值得你
No woman's worth...
為了她毀了一輩子
Ruining your life over.
聽著  夥計
Nah, man.
我和你說件事
I got one ting to say to you.
你這樣做是沒用的
That is lame.
沒用的?!
Lame?!
我給了那個女人6年的時光
I gave that woman six years of my life.
你知道什麼
Ah, what would you know?
你可能從來沒給過別人什麼
You've probably never given anybody anything.
-我給很多人東西  兄弟  -比如說?
- l've given nuff people stuff, blud. - like?
我一直給麥凱拉東西
I always give michela stuff.
我還給了布萊妮一些香水
Yeah, and l give briony some wicked perfume.
她很好滿足
She was well chuffed.
第二天  她走過來和我說  "迪..."
The next day, she come up to me, she said, ''d...
"迪  我只有19歲"
D, l'm only nineteen, yeah...
"我已經開始墮落了  無路可退了"
I'm on the game, l ain't got no place to live,
"上癮了"
I'm addicted to crack...
"但還有人送我香水"
But l got some wicked perfume on, boy''.
是不是就是她被殺了?
Wasn't she the one who got shot?
什麼  啊?
What? hm?
-那個女孩  我在海報上看到的  她...  -別說了
- the girl, l saw the poster, she... - you don't wanna be saying that shit.
我發誓  事實上  你還在這呆著幹嘛呢
I swear. you know, in fact, what are you still doing here, man?
你覺得被女人拋棄了  自己好像個小丑嗎
What? you feel like a prick cause your pride's been dented?
你覺得這事不可能發生在你身上
You didn't think it could happen to you!
-閉嘴  閉嘴  閉嘴  -你猜猜發生什麼了
- shut up. shut up. shut up. - well, guess what, mate?
-就是發生在你身上了  -你給我閉嘴
- lt fucking did. - hmmmmm! shut up!
你要買把槍去殺她的相好
You buying a gun to go and shoot her new man
別這樣 夥計 你要向前看 嗯？
Ain't gonna do jack, blud, so, just move on, yeah?
我不能繼續走下去
You...can't...just...move...on!
你可以  你老婆出走根本不能與我經歷的事相比
You can! your wife leaving you ain't shit compared to what l've been through.
-我和那個女人有個女兒  -這理由不錯
- l had a daughter with that woman! - that's a better reason.
不過就這理由來說  你就更不該
That's an even better reason for you to not want this...
要這個東西  你有個女兒啊
This...this ugly ting in your life. you got a little girl.
對  就是這麼回事  對吧?  就是這麼回事
Yeah, well, that's just it, isn't it? that's just it.
她不是我的女兒  她不是我的女兒
She isn't my little girl. she isn't my little girl!
現在你懂了沒
Now do you understand?!
兩年了
Two years.
兩年來  我一直以為我是她的爸爸
Two fucking years l spent thinking l was her dad.
現在卻發現我不是
And then l find out l'm not.
整整兩年了
Two fucking years!
別人才是她的爸爸
Some other fucker is.
那個人我認識
Someone l know.
我竟然認識他
Ohh, l fucking know him.
我竟然認識那個男人
I fucking know him!
最後我老婆為了他離開了我
And then my wife leaves me for him.
你知道那是什麼感覺嗎
Do you want to know how that feels?
我...  她是我女兒  她卻不是我親生的
I'm her...it's my daughter. she's not even mine.
我輾轉難寐
I'm lying awake at night.
我看完我以前日記
I'm going through my old diaries. l'm...
我想知道到底什麼時候開始的  我瘋了吧
I'm trying to figure out when it all began. l'm going out of my fucking mind...
操
Ohhh, shit.
給你  兄弟
Here you are, man.
有錢人  給你
Rich man, 'ere you are.
拿著  夥計  這是你的
Take it, blud. lt's yours. yeah?
我知道你生氣的原因了
Look, l hear your beef and that.
我知道你生氣的原因了  我明白的
I hear your beef, like, l understand.
但用槍  夥計
But this gun ting, man.
這可絕不是什麼好辦法
It...it just ain't the way.
兄弟  你得學著怎麼來應對這爛事
Bruv, you...you just gotta learn... you gotta learn how to deal with this shit,
向前看 對吧
And move on. yeah?
我挺過來了
I moved on.
千萬不要孩子氣
Never had no childhood.
我從十歲起就在孤兒院
I...l was in a children's home since l was ten.
那時只有我和我媽媽  兄弟
It was just me and my mum, blud.
嗯  她幹得可真是不錯
Well, she obviously did a great job.
-對不起  -你剛才說什麼
- l'm sorry. - what did you just say?
-你剛才說了什麼  -我不是有意的  只是...
- what did you say? huh? - l didn't mean it. l just...
-只是順口說說  對不起  -我媽媽盡了力
- lt just came out. l'm sorry. - my mum did the best job she could!
我會到孤兒院的唯一原因是她死了
The only reason l was in the children's home was 'cause she died.
想想我的感受
Think about how l felt.
被丟到了孤兒院
Dumped in a children's home.
沒有爸爸  媽媽也死了
No dad. dead mum.
我十歲的時候就完了
Even at the age of ten l was fucked!
為什麼我現在成這樣了  因為我的過去
That's why l'm here now! that's why! 'cause of my past!
而你  你是我見過的最有權勢的人
Look at y... you're the most privileged person l've ever met!
-他媽的  -聽著  我不...
- so, fuck you! - look, l didn't...
不  不  不
No. no, no, no, no.
操你媽  操你媽
Fuck you! fuck you!
如果你的人生和我一樣  你也不過是個煙鬼
If you lived my life, you'd be the same crackhead as me!
如果我有你的人生  即使我知道  也不會這樣
If l lived your life, blud, if l knew what l knew, l wouldn't be you.
你他媽個癮君子  你他媽個賤人
You fucking battie-boy crackhead! you fucking prick!
你完了  夥計
You're dead, blud!
兄弟  你要幹嘛  你要幹嘛  兄弟
What, blud? what you gonna do? what you gonna do, bruv?
你這個賤人  過來
Hey, you fucking prick, come here.
好  我知道  我知道
Yeah, l know. l know.
低點  放到這兒
Ah, ah, ah, lower down. down there, man.
保羅  注意你的手放在哪兒
Hey, paul. watch where you're putting your hands.
你摸的可是我的女人
that's my woman you're feeling up.
你感覺到了嗎
Can you feel it?
嘿  你過來
Hey, come 'ere, you...
快追  雷  快追
Just allow it. ray, man, just low it.
快點過去
Hey, man, just get over it.
格雷  夥計  衝過去
Gary, man, just allow it.
看  兄弟  看著我
Look, blud, blud, watch me.
堅持住  夥計  別這樣
Hold on, man. for fuck's sake.
我抓到他  我抓到他了  夥計
I got him. l got him, bruv.
操
Shit.
過來  你這個小...
Come here, you little...
全城最棒的
Best shit in town.
快點
Hey, gal, hurry up!
-我在這  兄弟  -夥計  快點!  打開那扇門
-  l'm here, bruv. -  man, hurry up! get that door, man!
-我來了  -他跑不了
-  l'm coming. -  he's got nowhere to go, blud!
他媽的賤人
Fucking wanker!
雷  他把門鎖了
Ray, he's blocked the door.
雷
Ray!
你跑不了的  夥計
You ain't got nowhere to go, blud!
媽的
What the fuck?
他脫了襯衫看起來真壯
Guess he looks hard with his shirt off though.
他看起來真棒
He looks great.
看那個
Look at that.
-準備好了?  -好了
-  ready? - ready, yeah.
你覺得很有趣嗎
You think you're funny, yeah?
哈  看看他
Ha-ha, look at him!
麥克·傑克遜!
Michael jackson! whooo-ooooo!
現在怎麼辦  嗯?
What you gonna do now, huh?
干他
Prick.
你跑不了
You got nowhere to go.
跑得可真夠遠的  我要把你從這扔下去
It's a long way down, innit? l'm gonna toss you down there.
-別  夥計  別  -你要幹什麼  兄弟
-  no, blud. no, man! -  what you gonna do, bruv?
我沒帶武士刀算你運氣好
You're lucky l didn't bring my samurai.
看他呀
Look at that.
放開他
Get off him!
我說  放開他
I said, get off him!
-你以為你能...  -雷  格雷
-  so...you....think...you...can...fuck.... - ray, gary!
雷  格雷
Ray, gary!
-我說放開他  -好  把槍放下  夥計
-  l said get off! -  all right, low it, blud.
放下  好嗎
Low it, yeah?
-我們得去找霍斯  -操
- we gotta go see the hood. - fuck this.
聽著  我不過賣些白粉來付我的大學學費
Listen, l'm a little weed dealer trying to pay my way through college.
-我可不是什麼騙子  -你會沒事的
- l ain't some fucking gyp. - oi, you'll chip it.
賽夫
Sef.
你是我的同伴啊  賽夫
You're my bredren, man. sef!
你為什麼那麼做  我簡直不敢相信
Why the fuck did you do that? l can't believe...
-做什麼  -你讓他們看到槍了
-  what? -  you showed them the gun, man.
-這全都是你的錯  -為什麼
- man, this is all your fault, yeah? - why?
因為如果昨晚你沒有來問我買槍
Cause if you never came up to me asking for a gun last night,
我們就不會捲進這事裡
We wouldn't be in this shit.
天哪  麥克  鸚鵡又不在窗台上
Fuck's sake, michael. the parrot ain't even in the window.
我得走了
Got to go.
輕點  輕點  把我放在這
Oh, easy, easy. put me down here, yeah.
啊  啊  輕點  操
Eh, eh, eh, easy. oh, shit.
操  你他媽是怎麼回事
Ah, fuck. what the fuck is wrong with you?
該死的脖子
Fucking neck!
操
Fuck off.
你他媽在幹什麼
What the fuck are you doing?
我看起來像在幹什麼  啊?
What does it look like l'm doing? huh?
我在找...粉 行嗎
I'm looking for...a rock, all right?
我記得 我發誓 我記得昨晚我在這丟了一些粉在這
I know, l swear, l know l lost a bit of rock in here last night.
看  我真的...
Huh... er, look, l really...
我可不認為那樣能解決一切
I don't think that's gonna solve anything.
你  你在說什麼  我要振奮一下  夥計
Wh...what y...you talking about? l need a toot, blud.
你不認為你該走了?  我說  你該走了
Don't you think you should leave? l said don't you think you should leave?
你說過他還會回來
You said he's going to come back.
我他媽的能去哪兒
Where the fuck am l meant to go?
我去哪裡?  我能往哪兒去?  啊?
Where am l going? where the fuck am l meant to go? huh?
呃  我只是...
Well, l just, er...
我不知道  總會有你能去的地方
I don't know, somewhere. there must be... must be somewhere you can go.
你還不明白  對吧
Don't get it, do you?
你有錢  所以你可以活下去
You can move on 'cause you got cash.
不  這不光和錢有關
No, it...it... lt isn't just about money.
不  就是錢的問題  兄弟
Yes, it is just about money, blud.
我們之間最大的不同是什麼?
What separates me and you?
錢  他媽的錢
Poverty. fucking poverty.
操  保羅
Oh, shit. paul.
肯定出事了  夥計
There's a problem, man.
行了  如果我說給你點錢的話?
All right. ok. what if... what if l said that l could get you money?
-什麼?  -如果我說給你錢呢?
- hm? - what if l got you money?
你覺得你就可以離開了嗎?
Then do you reckon you'd be able to leave?
你說過你再也搞不到錢給我了
You said you couldn't get me no more money.
-對 我說過  -那你到哪兒給我搞錢?
- yeah. l know. - where you gonna get me money from?
用這個
With this.
我可不干持械搶劫的事兒
I ain't doing no armed robberies.
不  不  不  我不是這個意思
No, no, no, no, no. l'm not talking about that.
那你是什麼意思?
So what are you saying?
他幹嘛到處找這把槍呢?
Why's he looking for the gun?
為什麼他這麼急著找這把槍  啊?
Why's he want the gun back so badly? hm?
行了  行了  我聽見你們的對話了
Oh, come on. come on. l heard what he said to you.
-他說了什麼  -他說這把槍是一件兇器
- what did he say? - that this gun is a murder weapon.
那又怎樣?
So?
所以  如果這把槍落到警察手裡呢?
So? what would happen if the police got hold of it?
我不會把槍給警察的
l ain't handing it in to no feds.
把槍還給我
Just give me the gun back.
我可沒說要把它交給警察
I'm not suggesting...l'm not suggesting we hand it in.
那你到底什麼意思?
So what you saying then, man?
我們手裡是有霍德維克的槍
W...we got hoodwink's gun, yeah?
那又怎樣
Wh...what do you want to do? huh?
拿著槍去勒索他嗎
You want to sell him his own gun back?
赫萊西奧  赫萊西奧
Horatio. Horatio.
他不會買自己的槍的  夥計
You don't sell hoodwink his own gun, blud.
幹嘛不?
Huh, huh. why not?
因為你不能
Cause you don't.
-為什麼  -因為他是個殺手
- why not? - ah, 'cause he's a killer.
他媽的  上帝啊
Jesus fucking christ!
你...
You...
我操你老娘
You motherfucker!
操你老娘
Motherfucker!
你憑什麼說他花錢拿回槍後
Hm... what's gonna stop him from... from buying the gun off you
不會一槍斃了你
And shooting you, blud?
-我把子彈拿掉  -什麼?
- well, I'll take the bullets out. - what?
我會把子彈取下來的
I'll take the bullets out.
他只是要槍  又不要子彈
He only wants the gun. he doesn't want the bullets.
他媽的
Oh, shit.
你就不能幫幫我嗎?
Will you help me, for christ's sake?!
-我在找白粉  -別管那破東西了
- I'm looking for my rock, man. - forget the crack.
-在這兒你找不到的  -我都快得癡呆了
- you're not going to find anything here. - shh. l got...bad man dementia.
你不是癡呆  而是瘋了
That's not dementia, that's demented.
我瘋了?
No. demented, yeah?
瘋的人是你  是你要把槍賣還給那個殺手
Demented is you trying to sell a killer back his own gun, blud. yeah?
現在這才是明智的  你知道嗎
This here is sensible, do you understand?
聽我說  我們必須離開  就現在
Listen to me. listen to me. we have got to leave now!
太棒了
Yes.
我找到了  現在看看是誰瘋了
I got it. who's demented now?
所有人都將見證巴比倫王朝的覆滅
All of the yout' shall witness the day babylon shall fall.''
回見  兄弟
Later, blud.
我操你媽
Fucking d! motherfucker!
你他媽的死定了  你這小混蛋
You're fucking dead, you little prick!
退後  他媽的給我退後
Back up! fucking back up!
別他媽的干蠢事  同性戀
Don't be fucking stupid, gaybo.
給我他媽的退後
Back the fuck up!
把槍放下  然後滾開
Put the gun down. and get out.
滾開  把槍放到地上  然後滾開
Get out. just put the gun down on the floor and get out.
我和你可沒什麼瓜葛  同性戀
Cause l ain't got no beef with you, gaybo.
不
No.
想要槍的話  用錢來換
If you want the gun, you're gonna have to pay for it.
我知道你幹嘛急著要這把槍
I know why you want this gun so badly.
-你他媽的跟他說什麼了  -給錢吧
- what the fuck have you been saying?! - so pay up.
是的  把錢給足了
Yeah. yeah, the whole lot.
不然我馬上就報警
Or l'm calling the police right now.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Ok. ok. ok.
過來拿錢
Come and get it.
你他媽的過來拿...
You come and get my...
這筆錢啊
..fucking money.
去啊
Go on.
拿啊
你敢碰一下我就殺了你
You pick up the fucking money, you're dead.
我不能
I can't.
他媽的
Shit.
哦  同性戀
Oh, gaybo.
-你他媽的放下他  -你死定了  我操死你
- oi! fucking get off him! - you're dead, you fucker!
-放下他  -我要殺了你...
- get off him! - you're fucking dead...
他媽的放了他
Get the fuck off him, man.
冷靜點 迪  冷靜
Calm down, d. calm down.
把刀放下
- hey, lose the blade, man.
他媽的給我把刀放下
leave the fucking blade!
-快啊  -好吧
- go on!  - ok, ok!
拜託  你看  我....
Come on, man. Look, I...I...
我知道你想要還我錢的  這我明白
I know you were trying to pay me back. l understand that.
求你了  迪  求你了
Please, d. please.
想想塔妮雅  我馬上就要...
Look at tania. l'm...l'm just about...
做爸爸了
Just about to become a dad. huh?
求你了  迪  別做蠢事
Please, d. pl... d, don't do nothing stupid.
想想我們還能一起拿白粉  就我們倆
Think. think of the rocks we could get, eh? you and me.
不是嗎
Huh?
到克裡斯托那兒去坐坐
Eh, go round crystal's, eh?
拿半袋白粉  再到我家裡
Get a nice half g stone. go back to my place.
-吸上一口  真是太棒了  -夠了  閉嘴
- have a toot. oh, it's beautiful. - stop it, man. stop. shut up. shut up!
多麼棒的煙啊
Nice pipe.
你知道那種深吸一口煙的美味
You know that...tight taste in your lungs.
棒極了  迪
Beautiful, d.
太美了  太棒了
Beautiful. beautiful.
把同性戀給殺了
Now shoot the gaybo.
來吧  迪  你行的
Come on, d. come on.
把該死的同性戀殺了  你就沒事了
Shoot the fucking gaybo and you are forgiven.
別  迪
No, d.
來吧  把同性戀殺了  他知道得太多了
Come on, shoot the gaybo. he...he....he knows too much.
他就要逃走了  殺了他呀  迪
He's gotta go. shoot the gaybo, d.
開槍啊
Sh-sh-sh-shoot!
-和你開槍殺wee briony一樣  -求你了  迪  別
- shoot him like you shot wee briony. -  please, d. please.
我可沒殺她
I didn't shoot her.
當然是你幹的
Course you did.
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no. no.
是你開槍殺了他
You shot her.
-拜託  -不  是你開的槍
- oh, come on, d... - no, you shot her!
迪  我們是一幫啊  你和我  迪和霍德
D. we're a team. huh? you and me. d and hoody. huh?
來吧   殺了這該死的同性戀
Now, come on, shoot the fucking gaybo!
當時可沒說要殺她  老兄
That weren't part of it, blud!
和講好的不一樣
It's not what you said to me.
可你想想  迪  布萊妮當時在威脅我
For fuck's sake, d. briony, she was... she was threatening me, right?
她從我這兒偷了錢還要去報警
She stole money off me, she threatened to go to the feds.
她要勒索我  你讓我怎麼辦  我都快有孩子了
She was trying to blackmail me. l couldn't have that, l've got a kid on the way.
-所以她必須死  -你怎麼能這樣說她  兄弟
- so she had to go. - what you talking about her like that, bruv?
那可是我的女人啊
My girl. that was my girl, yeah?
-霍斯  我愛她  -你愛他?
- hoods, l loved her. -  you loved her?
她是個不要臉的賤婆娘
She was a wee crackhead whore.
為了白粉她能跟男人上床
And she sucked cock for rock.
是我的錯
It's my fault, man.
我把她引到地下室
I coaxed her down into the basement.
他就在那兒等著
And he was waiting there.
我以為他只是嚇嚇她而已
I thought...l thought he was just gonna scare her, man.
他該死的說話不算數
He fucking lost it.
接著他就發瘋了  殺了她
He just went fucking mental, man. he shot her.
就這麼一槍殺了她
Just shot her.
迪?  迪
D? d.
我們該走了  馬上走
We gotta go. we gotta go.
不  赫萊西奧  不  你走吧
No, horatio. no. no. no. you go, yeah?
你走吧
You go.
這不是你該呆的地方  兄弟
This ain't your world down here, blud.
我們有錢了  可以走了
We got the money. we can leave.
去哪  兄弟  我他媽的能去哪呢
Go where, blud? where the fuck can I go? huh?
我犯事兒了  你不明白嗎
I've done bad, blud. don't you understand?!
他媽的走吧  我殺了很多人  你知道嗎
Just fuck off, yeah! l've gunned down nuff people, you know, blud!
-你走不走?  -好吧  好吧
- fuck off, yeah?! - ok, ok, ok, ok.
好吧
Ok. ok.
Ok.
-這兒我看著  -好吧  我走  我走
- I'll sort it. - all right. l'm going. l'm going.
你走吧
Just go, man.
拜託  迪  你也必須得走啊
Come on, d, you've gotta go too. please.
她躺在地上時的眼神歷歷在目
I can see her eyes, man. when she was laying on the floor.
你猜她眼睛告訴我什麼了
And you know what them eyes were saying?
以為我和你會永遠在一起
Thought me and you was tight, d.
永遠不分開
Me and you was tight.
我試圖救她的
I tried to help her, like.
但還是死了
She died, yeah?
只有她的眼睛在說話
She had the look in her eyes.
她說  "為什麼  迪"
She was saying, ''why, d?
"為什麼  迪"
Why? why, d?''
這就是我唯一得到的  唯一
That's how I know, that's how I know, yeah?
你得聽著  殺人什麼好處都沒有
Shooting someone ain't gonna bring nothing but badness.
我一直和你這麼說
I keep telling you this.
所以他媽的收手吧  忘了這一切
Just fuck it off, man. just forget it.
我沒想過要殺人
I wasn't going to shoot anybody.
我只想殺了我自己
I was gonna shoot myself.
為什麼  赫萊西奧
Why, horatio?
你又沒做過壞事
You ain't done nothing wrong.
我就不一樣了
Whereas...whereas l have.
你仍有重拾美好生活的希望
You...you still got a chance to have a nice life, blud.
而我卻沒有
Whereas l don't.
所以你收手吧
Just...sort out your shit, yeah?
求你了  湯姆
Please, tom.
走吧
Move on, yeah?
Move on, man.
我們都能繼續前進
We can all move on.
可以繼續下去
We can move on.
繼續生活
Just move on.
* breathe softly while you wait
* l won't be long
* l will stop the clock for you
* when l get home
* tenderness will pull you through
* lie gently while you wait
* l'll be there soon
* l'll build a fire for you
* when l get home
* we will rest
* and we will sleep ?